we know that until it's eradicated, polio remains a very real threat, especially to children in the poorest communities of the world. It can reemerge in some of the most remote and dangerous places, and from there, it can spread. And so this is my new Ironman: to end polio. And I am reminded every day, when I look at my two-and-a-half-year-old daughter Maya. She is able to climb a ladder in the park, push her scooter or kick a ball across the grass. Almost everything that I see her do at her age reminds me of what I could not do at that age. And when she was two months old, I took her to get her first polio vaccine. And when the doctor came in the room to prepare the shot, I asked him if I could take a picture to document the moment. When we left the room, I could feel my eyes welling up with tears. I cried the entire way home. It was in that moment that I realized that my daughter's life would be very different from mine. She will never be faced with the crippling disability of polio, because a vaccine was available, and I chose to get her immunized. She can do anything she wants, as can each of you. (Laughter) Now I'd like to leave you all with one question: what is your Ironman? Thank you. (Applause)
sabemos que hasta que se erradique, la polio sigue siendo una amenaza muy real, especialmente para los niños en las comunidades más pobres del mundo. Puede resurgir en algunos de los lugares más remotos y peligrosos, y a partir de ahí, se puede propagar. Y este es mi nuevo Ironman: acabar con la polio. Me viene a la mente todos los días, cuando miro a mi hija de dos años y medio, Maya. Ella es capaz de subir una escalera en el parque, empujar su scooter o patear una pelota sobre la hierba. Casi todo lo que la veo hacer a su edad me recuerda lo que no pude hacer a esa edad. Y cuando ella tenía dos meses, la llevé a que le pusieran su primera vacuna contra la polio. Y cuando el médico entró a la habitación para prepararla, le pregunté si podía tomar una foto para documentar el momento. Cuando salimos de la habitación, pude sentir mis ojos llenándose de lágrimas. Lloré todo el camino a casa. Fue en ese momento que me di cuenta de que la vida de mi hija sería muy diferente a la mía. Ella nunca se enfrentará con la paralizante discapacidad de la polio, porque existe una vacuna y elegí vacunarla. Ella puede hacer lo que quiera, como lo pueden cada uno de Uds. (Risas) Ahora me gustaría dejarles a todos con una pregunta: ¿Cuál es su Ironman? Gracias. (Aplausos)